"Namu Amida Butsu"
"Namu Amida Butsu" Believe it or not,
the world is filled with strange phenomena
Believe it or not, the world is
filled with strange phenomena
that science has yet to explain.
And when people come
face to face with them,
they are helplessly thrown
into the dark depths of fear.
But there are those who fight every day
to shine a ray of hope
into that chaotic darkness.
People call them...
"Yokai Hunters"
..."Yokai hunters"!
This is the city...
The city with the Divine Tree that
was featured on that talk show.
Now, then...
Who knows what monstrosities await?
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
I realized that my youth was grey
The root of this irritation is unknown
My brain runs parallel with this emotional train
Struggling adolescence
Don't disturb the subconscious mind
Who's that behind me?
Opposing ideas, distortion
Purge the sorrow
So, do what you can now.
My life
Finally
Break it down!!
(WANT) desire (YOUNG) and sincerity
(BURN) they begin to sprout (1) within my chest
(TRANCE) I won't awaken (CHANCE) but I want to
(STANCE) both sides of the coin
(1) are back-to-back
Accept me as I am
Conflicting freedom and relations
If they can become one
That smile will be
One and only "1"
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
"Mob Psycho 100 III"
MOB MOB WOW!
One and only "1"
"Mob Psycho 100 III"
"Mob Psycho 100 "
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
One and only "1"
"Yokai Hunter Amakusa Haruaki Appears!
- The Threat of a Hundred Demons!!~"
"Cultural Fair
Haunted House Job List"
"Cultural Fair Haunted House Job
List" Who doesn't have a job yet?
Who doesn't have a job yet?
Well, if you don't have any preferences...
Niido-kun, Sagure-kun,
Kageyama-kun, and Inukawa-kun,
you'll be in charge of the costumes.
That sucks!
"Costumes Niido I Sagure I
Kageyama I Inukawa" That sucks!
"Costumes
Niido I Sagure I Kageyama I Inukawa"
"Costumes Niido I Sagure I Kageyama I Inukawa" The costumes
will be the key to success with this haunted house,
"Costumes
Niido I Sagure I Kageyama I Inukawa"
so make sure you give it your all.
Can't we just use sheets?
Can't we just put white sheets over
our heads and go, "We're spooky ghosts"?
Yeah! Then we don't have
to bother making anything.
Niido... You're just...
...an absolute genius!
Isn't this great, Mob? We won't
be stuck in sewing hell now!
Er, is that really okay, though?
We're just going to give the people
playing ghosts white cloths?
Since we're in charge of costumes,
shouldn't we be doing a little bit more?
What the hell, Kageyama?
Then are you able to make anything,
or come up with any ideas?
If you can, then tell us.
"Buh buh buh buh"
--Buh, buh, buh, buh...
"Buh buh buh buh" --I don't hear anything, do you?
--I don't hear anything, do you?
--Buh, buh, buh, buh...
"Progress Toward
Mob's Explosion"
"Costume Idea: Sheets it is"
"Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 22%"
"Student Council Office"
Anyone handling food at the cultural
fair will need a fecal exam done,
so make sure you let
the class reps know that.
Sir.
What is it, Kageyama-kun?
I think the things we're doing
this year are a bit extreme.
"Salt Middle School Booth or Event by Class" I think
the things we're doing this year are a bit extreme.
"Salt Middle School Booth or Event by Class"
"Salt Middle School Booth or Event by Class" The concert venue
is definitely going to cause a noise issue with the neighborhood.
"Salt Middle School Booth or Event by Class"
Not to mention...
A cross-dressing café?!
This is the cultural fair, so we should
have everyone dress more conservatively!
"O/X Student Council Meeting" This is the cultural fair,
so we should have everyone dress more conservatively!
"O/X Student Council Meeting"
"O/X Student Council Meeting" I think
that's fine, as long as everyone's safe.
I think that's fine,
as long as everyone's safe.
--Wha--?
--I agree,
but just in case,
let's remind everyone again.
Is everyone okay with that?
Yes...
And so time passed,
"Psycho Helmet Religion”
"Newspaper" And so time passed,
"Newspaper"
and right about when there were only
two weeks until the cultural fair...
Preparations have been going smoothly...
...and at this rate, that's not good.
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office" "The star psychic of the 21st century
and Seasoning City's Big Bro!!" "Welcome to Reigen Arataka's homepage!!
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office" "The star psychic of the 21st century and Seasoning City's Big
Bro!!" "Welcome to Reigen Arataka's homepage!! This isn't good. I need to think of some promotion.
This isn't good. I need to
think of some promotion.
The visitors to the site have been...
Here you go.
Oh, thanks. So what did
you want to talk about?
Well...
"Evening Middle School” "Why don't you try out our classes?” "'We'll
support everyone's dreams!' We customize everyone's lesson plans"
support everyone's dreams!' We customize everyone's lesson plans" I see.
I see.
So you want to go here? That seems sudden.
I'm thinking about redoing
my compulsory education.
It's a night school,
so I'll have to be off by 4 PM...
He's trying to improve himself, huh?
Sounds good.
Why don't you give it a try?
Th-Thank you very much!
Well, I've got Mob, so we'll figure it out.
"Reception”
As for Dimple...
I haven't seen him around lately.
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office" As for
Dimple... I haven't seen him around lately.
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office"
I should've put a leash on him.
Hullo! I am the Yokai hunter Amakusa Haruaki!
"Yokai Hunter Amakusa Haruaki"
--Mama, look at that guy.
--That's what I'll say as I go in.
--Stop staring.
--Why?
--That's what I'll say as I go in.
Hullo! I am...
Hullo! Hullo! My name is Amakusa...
Okay!
Huwwo!
H-Hullo! My nyame is Amakusa Haruaki!
Can I help you?
My mission is... Oh, right, since I'm here...
...I can say that I hunt those
who writhe in the shadows...
The reason I came to this city is to stop
"the incident" before it can start.
I didn't understand 90% of what he just said.
I'm terribly sorry, but I have an appointment
with a client who's ordered an exorcism.
Would you mind waiting outside?
I'm probably the last person who should
say this, but he sure was unique...
He's being questioned by the police.
Yeah, he's gonna get taken to the station.
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office"
"3 hours later"
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office" "3
hours later" Sensei! Thank you so much!
Sensei! Thank you so much!
Let's go ahead and take a break.
Oh, sure.
Are you free now?
It's me, Amakusa Haruaki.
So they didn't take him away...
Now, then...
Let us discuss the... dark army.
So not those who writhe in the shadows?
They have more than one name.
You should also not mention them so casually.
You will fall prey.
The vortex of madness is definitely spreading.
In order for us to break free
from this cycle of sadness,
I implore that you assist me.
Um... I'm sorry. You may be a client,
but I don't quite understand--
I am not a client.
Huh?
I am the one who, er...
hides in the... darkness...
Um...
I am the one who hunts the evil
that hides in the darkness!
I am the Yokai hunter Amakusa Haruaki!
Shut up!
It's annoying as hell trying to hear you
fit in all of these buzz words!
B-But I'm not...
Stop finding gratification from picking the most
confusing phrasing each time, you dumb-ass!
I don't have time to listen to your nonsense!
If you don't hurry up and tell me
what you want or leave,
I'm gonna rip off them
side buns in your hair!
A-All right...
7 In this world, there abound evil Yokai
who threaten the peaceful lives of the masses. 7
71, Amakusa Haruaki, am a Yokai hunter 7
7 who rends these Yokai for evermore. 7
7 I traveled to Seasoning City
for I sensed the presence of Yokai here. 7
I am currently after the evil Yokai horde,
the Hundred Demons.
Their goal is the resurrection
of the Great Yokai King,
so they are preparing to steal away
as much energy as possible.
At some point, he just
started speaking normally.
It was probably too difficult.
This ominous presence grows greater
by the day, and I am panicking.
Why not talk to the police about this?
The police are bad news.
They will immediately try to use
the Firearms and Swords Control Act
against me and try to capture me!
"The Firearms and Swords Control Act" "“Violation" the Firearms
and Swords Control Act against me and try to capture me!
"The Firearms and Swords Control Act"
"Violation"
Well, of course they will.
--A-Anyway, I would like for your aid
in slaying the Hundred--
--You can't be serious!
--A-Anyway, I would like for your aid in slaying the Hundred--
I don't have time for any more of your games.
I'm trying to run a business here!
Go on, scram already.
Oh, will you help me if I
pay you a consultation fee?
Will a million yen be enough?
You really think you can fool me
with this writing pad?
"10,000 yen"
Th-They're real?!
My parents are rather wealthy
and support my lifestyle.
All right, Serizawa. Let's go!
Huh?
We're goin' Hundred Demons hunting!
If the Great Yokai King is resurrected,
this world will fall into darkness!
"Madness" If the Great Yokai King is
resurrected, this world will fall into darkness!
"Madness"
We must vanquish the vortex of madness...
...and break free from this cycle of sadness!
Y-Yes, sir!
Wow, I'm so happy... I've made friend.
Yokai hunters are forever alone.
I have been fighting solo this whole time.
This is the first time I've experienced
kindness from another in a very long while.
I thank you.
Hey, Mob. What's up?
Oh, pardon me. I was hoping
I could talk to you, Master.
Sure, right after we finish this job.
You're coming with us.
What are we doing?
We're slaying Yokai!
We're gonna break free
from this cycle of sadness.
Right...
My apologies, boy.
This is an emergency.
Women and children should stay behind.
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office"
Don't worry. Mob will be fine.
Another dud.
This guy better not just be
some random cosplayer.
Though I guess I don't care
as long as I get paid.
There! I sense a very faint presence
of a demonic aura from there!
--Hey, we had a job to exorcise an evil spirit from this abandoned building before.
--We've still got a lot to prepare...
--The evil spirit did disappear, didn't it?
--We don't have much time.
--There's only two weeks left...
for the costumes and sewing...
--I do actually sense some weird energy from there.
--There's only two weeks left... for the costumes and sewing...
I see.
Welp, let's go.
Come to think of it, what is our
costume-making budget?
This is the place...
There's no doubt about it!
"Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 31%"
The atmosphere in here has transformed.
The Yokai must be behind this.
Curse you, Hundred Demons. They must
be plotting to make this their lair.
Are there really Yokai here?
Was this guy not just some cosplayer?
The roots of some plant?
What's wrong, Amakusa?
You're sweating bullets.
Well, you see...
I only have experience
fighting Yokai one-on-one.
And every time,
it's a life-or-death situation.
Even against solo Yokai, I made sure
to prepare as much as possible,
and was able to slay them...
after three days and three nights.
But this time...
...we are in the lair of the Hundred Demons
Yokai horde, which means...
What's wrong?!
This wall's all slimy!
Maybe if we hang some konjac up,
it'll scare people!
--Wha--?!
--What's wrong?!
The path we came from is--
It's been closed off.
I guess we'll have to take down
whatever's messing up this area.
You seem calm about this, Serizawa.
Oh, I tend to feel more relaxed
in dark, confined spaces.
We can use cardboard and duct tape...
We'll have to measure the height
of the people playing the ghosts.
Anyway, we'll just have
to keep moving forward.
Hope you're prepared, Yokai hunter.
My stomach feels all stabby...
Reigen, behind you!
So you've shown yourself, Yokai!
Something or other, something
or other, O some kind of spirit!
"Holy Blade Kusanagi-no-Dai-Hannya-Kagemitsu"
"(Tax Included)"
"(Tax Included)" Give me strength!
Give me strength!
"Holy Blade!
Kusanagi-no-Dai-Hannya-Kagemitsu”
"Holy Blade! Kusanagi-no-Dai-Hannya-Kagemitsu"
Holy Blade! Kusanagi-no-Dai-Hannya-Kagemitsu!
Holy Blade!
Kusanagi-no-Dai-Hannya-Kagemitsu!
My holy blade!
Ah... so it's basically
like a normal exorcism.
What on Earth is that power?
Now there're tons of them!
They're all coming at once!
We're in so much danger that my
brain has stopped functioning...
I'm going to use salt to weaken them.
The rest is up to you, Serizawa and Mob!
Yes, sir!
Take this!
Salt Splash!
Oh, maybe we could use
purified salt for something fun.
I see...
If we can defeat the ghosts,
the kids might enjoy that.
Th-That's...
The four generals of the Hundred Demons!
And behind them... is the Great Yokai King!
He's already been
brought back to this realm?!
Foolish humans...
They are the four generals
of the Hundred Demons.
They will cast you all into
the deepest depths of despair.
W-We're done for...
I'm sorry for dragging you into this...
Well, if we're in that much trouble,
let's make a break for it.
I don't think that's possible, actually.
True. I don't think I have enough
creativity to design that...
They took two down instantly?
Just who are those two?
They're psychics.
Incredible power like that
exists in this world...?
I'm so envious.
You'd think it's worth
being envious of, right?
But to them, apparently,
it's not incredible at all.
Not only have you defeated
my Hundred Demons,
you've defeated my four generals...
Not bad, humans...
But...
...don't believe for a second...
...that you can defeat the Great Yokai King!
Y-You two are so powerful...
Any interest in becoming Yokai hunters?
Of course, I'll make sure
you're paid every month.
What?! Hey, you two--
Yeah, I don't think so. I want to study.
I'm sorry.
My head is currently full of thoughts
concerning the cultural fair.
Cultural fair...?
Heh. Too bad for you.
They're too busy trying
to live their daily lives.
Amakusa...
If you think you can use
your money to win over everyone,
you're gravely mistaken!
Reigen, my apologies!
You believed what I had to say as a friend,
and yet, I tried to buy
your help with money!
Please forgive my foolishness!
Er, hey, wait!
I'm absolutely okay with
getting a consultation fee--
I-I see. I'm glad you understand.
Reigen... I thank you from
the bottom of my heart.
You know, this is a rather freaky design.
I wonder if I could stuff this and sell it...
Huh?
Well, it is an ayakashi.
It will eventually turn into ash.
Oh, really.
That's it!
That guy was a real Yokai hunter, huh?
I guess there are all kinds
of jobs in the world.
Why don't we grab some ramen and head home?
Oh, I actually have something to do.
Hm? Wait, what did you want to talk about?
It's okay. I figured it out.
Please excuse me.
Mob solved something on his own...
Inukawa-kun.
I got an idea for the costumes,
so could you come to class
early tomorrow morning?
Huh?! Didn't we decide
on the white sheets?
No. We need to do everything we can.
"Great Yokai King"
Everyone else is doing their own job, too.
"Just xx days until the fair!!"
"Let's do our best!!"
"Great Yokai King Design by: Kageyama
Shigeo, Inukawa Mameta, Niido, Sagure"
"Salt Middle School Cultural Fair"
And then, on the day of the cultural fair...
"Reception”
"Reception” The costume that Mob and
Inukawa created got a lackluster response,
The costume that Mob and Inukawa
created got a lackluster response,
but no one complained about it, either.
"Haunted House" "Entrance to Hell"
"Use salt on the ghosts to defeat them"
"Haunted House" "Entrance to Hell" "Use salt on the ghosts
to defeat them" As for what the customers thought...
As for what the customers thought...
I see... This is pretty fancy
for a middle school fair.
"Ancestral Grave" "Route" I see... This
is pretty fancy for a middle school fair.
"Ancestral Grave" "Route"
That sure is a freaky design...
I'm glad we did this.
Yeah.
I'm exhausted, though.
Yeah, this was great.
"Today's Maids"
Thanks for waiting.
Here is your Mr. Bear's Very Beary Soda,
and your Daydreaming Bunny
Wunny's Hippity Hop Cola.
Oh, this is so cute!
All the boys are maids!
I'm gonna take a picture!
Enjoy your stay.
Party of one coming in!
Yo, Ritsu...
Th-That's one hell of a getup.
Though it looks pretty good on you.
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office"
All right. That should do it.
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office" "The star psychic of the 21st century who defeated
The Great Yokai King!!" "Welcome to Reigen Arataka's homepage!! All right. That should do it.
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office" "The star psychic of the 21st century
who defeated The Great Yokai King!!" "Welcome to Reigen Arataka's homepage!!
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office" "The star psychic of the 21st century who defeated The
Great Yokai King!!" "Welcome to Reigen Arataka's homepage!! That should hike up those page views.
That should hike up those page views.
"The Great Yokai King" "The leader of the evil Yokai horde
known as the "Hundred Demons." It has red eyes and sharp fangs.”
There was a blue light shining
I'm wide awake this 1:30 AM
What remained even after I swiped
Are the smiles of my friends right beside me
Yes, I want someone to understand...
This wish that's hidden colorless and invisible
The breath I was holding deep within my heart
I let it all out at once and return to my senses
On days that I'm feeling apathetic
it suddenly comes to mind
These seasons I spent as if they were a given
Even if reality becomes sullied
Only the sky we saw together is real
This is more incomprehensible
Than the grammar on the blackboard
If it's going to disappear within 24 hours
This flowing story is just too lonely
I just can't do it
Just like that back hip circle I gave up on
But I'm not going to...
Give up
My present anymore
I adorn my overflowing emotions
And run through my worries and hesitations
It can't be decided from 0 to 100
Draw the incomplete future with this hand
We can't even prove its existence
But as the world stabs the middle of my chest
It overflows with cobalt blue
English Translator: Michelle Tymon Translation Editor:
Zachary Carlysle Translation Checker: Sriram Gurunathan
What? Mob's time has finally arrived?
He's so popular with girls, he doesn't know what
he's gonna do and he's gonna become the founder?
Go forth, Mob!
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 Il Episode 3:
"Getting Carried Away
- 100%~."
Recording it? That's also a wise decision.
"Getting Carried Away - 100%~"
"Getting Carried Away
- 100%~"